=As Promised=
(Adapted from "The Villain's Guide to Love",
a story on Zhihu Yanyan)
=Episode 9=
I hope you won't
laugh at me, Your Highness.
Tingting steps gracefully
[*Tingting: a pun on graceful poise]
from behind the gauze curtains,
her beauty captivating every eye.
You
must be Mu Tingting.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
during the Lantern Festival,
you left the palace in disguise.
I assume you're here to see
how the people are faring.
There's plenty to enjoy outside.
- Why don't we go outside
- Fu Yang.
and take the opportunity
to join the people in the festivities?
Yes, let's!
Then let's hurry out and have some fun.
Come on, Yuan Yuan.
Miss Mu, why don't you
come with us?
May I?
Candied hawthorns!
Yuan Yuan, candied hawthorns!
Yuan Yuan!
Candied hawthorns!
Miss, have a look.
Fragrance sachets!
This lantern is so beautiful.
Come have a look! Fragrance sachets!
Come take a look!
Hand-embroidered fragrance sachets!
Where are they?
No, there are too many people here.
Those two girls are on their own.
They could be in danger.
Let's split up and look for them.
Come take a look!
Excuse me!
Young lady,
it must be lonely walking by yourself.
How about I enjoy the lanterns with you?
How dare you!
What do you think you're doing?
This is rather interesting.
What do you think I want?
I like you.
My wife is shy around strangers.
Sir,
please behave yourself.
Come take a look!
Let's go.
Look!
It's so lively!
Let's go take a look over there.
Come on!
Follow me.
Fu Yang.
What did you just call me?
Wife?
It was only a temporary measure.
Forgive me for the offense,
Your Highness.
What if, of all the people in the world,
you're the only one
I'll allow to offend me?
When you saved me just now,
I already saw it.
On this Lantern Festival,
a golden hairpin for a beautiful lady.
Fu Yang,
this hairpin...
Were you planning to give it to me?
I'll count to three.
If you don't answer,
I'll take that as a yes.
One.
Two, three.
It's mine now.
Since you've given it to me,
you can't take it back.
Fu Yang,
I want you, three days from now,
to ask my mother
for permission to marry me.
If you don't come,
I'll never bother you again.
♪My thoughts
of you linger by the window♪
Your Highness, rest here for a while.
I'll go find He Xiaoyuan.
♪Green glazed hues,
red strokes of the brush♪
♪The pages hold a heart steadfast
from beginning to end♪
He Xiaoyuan,
have you lost your mind?
Why did you invite Mu Tingting along?
You planted spies to keep track
of the Crown Prince
and learned that he was coming
to the pleasure house,
so you planned to get here first
and keep the two of them from meeting.
Unfortunately,
they still met.
Zhao Boqing,
if I hadn't brought
Mu Tingting out with us,
would she
already be dead by now?
Sometimes I truly don't know
whether to call you foolish
or clever.
If you figured it out,
why did you stop me?
Because she hasn't done anything wrong.
The Crown Prince likes her.
That's not her fault.
You're killing an innocent person.
He Xiaoyuan,
nothing you say now
will make a difference.
I won't allow anyone
to ruin my plans.
Is the fact that I like you
also getting in the way of your plans?
What does that
have to do with you liking me?
Stop.
If you dare kill Mu Tingting,
I'll take my own life
right now and start over.
He Xiaoyuan,
how long are you going
to let compassion cloud your judgment?
Don't you understand?
As long as
Mu Tingting alone is sacrificed,
no one will be able to threaten
your position as Crown Princess.
In exchange, the realm can enjoy peace
and the nation can prosper.
How easy it is to say,
"sacrifice one person."
Who would willingly become
a sacrifice for your grand plans?
The realm, power,
and position you seek to protect,
aren't they all
made up of countless individuals?
Fine.
You win.
I won't kill her.
Satisfied?
But
as for your feelings for me,
bury them deep
and never speak of them again.
We belong to different worlds.
Go find the Crown Prince.
Mother, wake up! Mother!
Mother!
Don't be afraid.
He Xiaoyuan.
Watch out!
He Xiaoyuan!
Murder!
Wait here for me.
- Hurry!
- Go!
- Murder!
- Hurry!
- Go!
Quick.
Run toward the south alley.
On your left,
turn right at the third fork.
It's the house with a well.
All right.
He Xiaoyuan,
hold on.
Consider my childhood debt
to you repaid.
Who asked you to repay me?
Your life belongs to me.
If I won't let you die,
then you absolutely cannot die.
You're the one I love.
I never wanted
to pursue Zhao Junyao at all.
In the next life...
He Xiaoyuan!
♪One thought waits for the snow,
shining bright in my memories♪
Quick!
Be good and take this. Hurry!
♪With no regrets for this chapter♪
♪Can I still hope that someday
we'll meet again?♪
He Xiaoyuan.
Wake up.
If you don't wake up,
I'll have your parents join you.
I mean it.
He Xiaoyuan.
What can you do
besides threaten me?
Yes.
That's how despicable I am.
So you're not allowed to die.
If you die,
who will be the one variable
in this game of mine?
Who will annoy me and make me angry?
He Xiaoyuan,
I have feelings for you.
So please,
please stay alive.
What did you say?
Only in this lifetime
have I finally understood my own heart.
I'm in love with you.
It has nothing to do with the Crown Prince
or the fate of the realm.
Please,
don't leave me.
How do you feel?
Is this my final burst of life?
Before people die,
can they really see the person
they most want to see?
Your Highness.
I'm so happy
I get to see you before I die.
Then I can help you find out
whether you're still alive.
Do you still think
this is your final burst of life?
I must be dead.
Silly He.
♪My longing has nowhere to rest♪
♪Through the storm, I drift and sway♪
♪You are the prayer I hold in my palm♪
♪In one frozen moment,
my tears come into focus♪
♪My heart has long known♪
♪We made a promise long ago♪
♪To stay together until the end of time♪
♪You are the fate I cannot escape♪
♪How much must I let go♪
♪For one moment♪
♪To hold each other close♪
♪Would that be enough?♪